他们自称为Genii
They call themselves the Genii.
他们很淳朴，
但擅长农业和商业
They are a simple people,
but good farmers and fair traders.
离我们从新大陆那儿
We're still months away
获得收成还有几个月的时间
from producing successful crops on the mainland,
我们将面临食物短缺的状况
and we're heading towards a food shortage.
情况越来越糟了
It's getting desperate.
我们的咖啡快用完了
We're almost out of coffee.
也许你该改一下每天喝11杯咖啡的习惯了
Well, maybe you should stop drinking 11 cups a day.
我只是想在咖啡用尽之前用完
自己应得的份额
I'm just making sure I get
my fair share before it's all gone.
听起来不错嘛
Sounds fair.
我完全赞成交易
但难道你们不认为
I'm all for trade, but don't you think we should find
我们该找到加强防御的方法吗？
a way to help defend ourselves?
一群农民怎么能做到这一点？
How can a bunch of farmers do that?
也许他们可以介绍些可以帮助我们的人
Well, maybe they can introduce us
to people who can help.
同时，我们继续守卫好基地
In the meantime, let's take care of the basics.
我认为多了解下自己的邻居没有坏处
I guess it's always good to get to know your neighbors.
Genii人的星际门在他们的村庄的不远处
The Genii's stargate is
a short distance from their village.
我们可以步行过去
I suggest we walk.
探险者号也许会让他们心生疑惑
The puddle jumper may alarm them.
正如我说的，他们是非常淳朴的
As I said, they are very simple.
看起来颇具挑战呀
Sounds like a mission.
好了
All right.
Teyla，我们现在去哪儿？
Where to, Teyla?
我们需要让他们靠近先我们
We should allow them to come to us.
如果你知道他们的村庄在哪里的话……
Well, if you know where the village is...
他们是非常淳朴的人，他们很信任我
但这种信任不是轻易获得的
They are simple people and they trust me,
but that trust was hard earned.
OK
Okay.
你上次说他们都种了些什么来着？
What is it you said they grow here, anyway?
很多啊，最出名的就是一种
叫做“塔瓦”的豆子
Many things, but they are best
known for a bean known as tava.
什么？爪哇？
What, java?
是塔瓦
Tava.
那他们怎么能知道我们到这儿了呢
How will they even know we're here, anyway?
他们已经知道了
They already do.
他们看起来很友好
They look friendly enough.
最老的一个叫做Tyrus
The eldest one is called Tyrus.
我已经有多次和他交易的经验
I've traded with him on many occasions.
Teyla Emmagan
Teyla emmagan.
Tyrus
Tyrus.
好久不见了
It has been many days.
是很久了
Too many.
Teyla
Teyla.
这位是……
This is...
Sheppard少校
Major Sheppard,
McKay博士
Dr. Mckay,
还有Ford少尉
and lieutenant Ford.
我的女儿，Sora
My daughter, Sora.
有这么个女儿你一定很骄傲
You must be very proud.
她已经许配给人了
She is betrothed.
呃，我不是对你的女儿有意
我只是……
Well, I wasn't hitting on your daughter.
I just...
他们是来和你们交易的
They have come to trade for a share of your crops.
但你们带了武器
Yet you bring weapons.
我们只是自卫
Only to defend ourselves.
你穿和他们一样的服装是自愿的吗？
Do you dress as they do of your own accord?
当然，有问题吗？
Of course. Why?
他想知道你是和我们一伙的还是
帮我们的忙而已
He wants to know if you work with us or for us.
Tyrus，他们是我的朋友
These are my friends, Tyrus.
如果我觉得他们不值得成为你们的朋友的话
我是不会带他们来的
I would not have brought them if I did not
think them worthy to become yours.
我们带你们去见Cowen
We'll take you to see Cowen.
跟我来
Follow me.
也许我们应该多谢幽默感
Maybe we should offer a sense of humor in trade.
当然，你可以试试
Sure. They can have yours.
哦，伙计，别逗我了
Oh, please, my side.
You slayed me.
我正在考虑
I'm thinking about it.
我现在带他们进去
所有设备进入静音状态
I'm bringing them in.
All operations to silent mode.
星际之门之亚特兰蒂斯
第一季第8集 地下基地
Season 1 : Episode 8
Underground
这些药有效吗？
And these medicines are potent?
它可以用来完全防止细菌感染
They are capable of stopping
bacterial infections entirely.
对于度过寒冷的冬天极有帮助
It would help us through a harsh winter.
我们需要比你们提供的更多
We will need more than you offer.
更多？
More?
你们不知道这药有多灵
I don't think you understand how cool this medicine is.
如果不愿意的话你们可以离开
Well, leave if you wish.
离开？
Leave?
你不是说Genii人是很好的交易伙伴吗？
I thought you said the Genii were fair traders.
以前我们总是能谈一个
双方都能接受的价格
We have always been able
to achieve a reasonable bargain.
你们要我们收成的大部分
You ask for much of our harvest.
我们需要大量的种植新的作物来补充储藏
New crops will have to be
planted in sufficient quantities
否则饿死的就是我们Genii人
to replenish our stores,
or it is the Genii who will starve.
新作物的种植需要大量的新田地
That amount of planting will
require new land to be cleared.
开垦新田地是一项缓慢而艰苦的工作
Clearing more land is slow, hard work,
and it will lose us a great amount
而我们也将损失许多这个和下个季度
之间的时间
of growing time between now and
the next harvest season.
好吧
Okay.
如果我们能让开垦变得快而容易呢？
What if clearing land was fast and easy?
你们知道怎么能很快地
掘起一棵百年老树的深根吗？
You know a simple way of uprooting
the stump of a 300 year-old tree?
很不幸的告诉你……我知道
As a matter of fact... I do.
捂住你们的耳朵
Cover your ears.
为什么啊
I don't understand.
会有很大声音
It can be quite loud.
快点，否则你们会后悔的
Come on. You're going to wish you did.
少尉？
Lieutenant?
点火
Fire in the hole.
这叫C-4
It's called C-4.
如果你们可以给我们提供足够的C-4
If you can supply us with a sufficient quantity of C-4,
我们就能够向你们提供足够的作物
we will supply you with the crop you require.
那么，就不用那些药了？
So, this instead of the medicine?
药也要
As well as the medicine.
不会吧？
Really?
这还不够吗？
That wasn't impressive enough?
有需求的是你们
It is you who are in need.
那我得回去和他们商量一下
Well, I'll have to discuss this with my people.
我相信我们可以达成协议的
I'm sure we can come to terms.
Teyla，很感谢你给我们带来了
新的贸易伙伴
Teyla, thank you for bringing us
these new trading partners.
留下来，我们要好好款待你
Please stay as our guests.
我们稍后有个丰收庆典
There will be a harvest ceremony later.
棒极了
Wonderful.
Ford?
长官？
Sir?
我们在说丰收庆典
We're talking harvest ceremony.
长官，听起来很有趣
Sounds like fun, sir.
我一会儿回来
I'll be back soon.
我要和少校回去一趟
I should go back with the major.
爆炸物？
Explosives?
少校，这可是科学探险
This is a scientific expedition, Major.
我知道
I know that.
但你现在正变成一个军火商
But you want us to become arms dealers.
那你可以用手把树根拔起吗？
Have you ever tried to clear a stump by hand?
可以啊，这是我的业余爱好
Yes. It's a hobby.
他们在考虑把今年收成的
大部分卖给我们
They are taking a chance by giving us
so much of their crop this year.
而且还要加上我上次同意的那些药品？
Plus the medicines I already agreed to?
少校，也许下次我该亲自参与谈判了
I think in the future, major,
I should do the negotiating.
我不是来先请示你了么
I did say I had to ask you first.
是啊，请示我那些你已经同意的条款
Uh-huh, to terms you already agreed to.
没错
Yes.
你知道我为什么有意见吗？
Do you see why I have a problem with this?
那我们还需不需要食物了？
Do we need food or not?
我们的配给快用完了
We are on the verge of rationing, and as much
而我也在尽力的在外星探险中寻找塔瓦
as I'd like to devote every off-world mission
to the pursuit of tava beans...
我明白你的意思了
I get your point.
告诉他们我们答应了
Tell them we agree.
我们为了这次丰硕的收成而感恩
We give thanks for a plentiful harvest.
我们感恩
We give thanks.
祝愿下个季节一样收成满满
May next season be as fruitful.
还有为我们的新朋友干杯
And to our new friends.
为新朋友干杯
To new friends.
自酿的烈酒？
Moonshine?
我还以为你够man呢
I thought you were man enough.
你不知道我们该怎么走，是吧？
You have no idea which way to go, do you?
我正寻找发现
Just trying to get my bearings.
也就是说，“我迷路了”
Translation, "I'm lost."
他们当时走的很果断
They were very clear which route to take.
我喜欢走直路
I prefer a straight line.
是啊，当然，Sheppard少校总能找到捷径
Yes, of course, because everything's
a shortcut in Sheppard's world.
OK，又来了
Okay, there it is again.
什么？
What?
我收到一个从那儿传来的奇怪的信号
I'm picking up a strange reading
from right over there.
怎么个奇怪法？
Define strange.
你不知道奇怪是什么意思吗？
You don't know what strange means?
Rodney，我知道奇怪是什么意思
I know what strange means, Rodney...
怪异，奇特，古怪……
Weird, freakish, odd...
我正在考虑是否值得让我们放弃
寻找回村庄的道路
I'm just trying to determine whether it's worth
getting off the route back to the village.
奇怪的放射信号，你说呢
Radioactive readings on amish world. You call.
——反正我们现在迷路了，不会有什么影响的
——我没有……
- We're lost anyway. What difference is it?
- I am not...
迷路
lost.
好吧，我们来查查看
All right, let's check it out.
哦，现在我们可以说，确实很
Oh, now, that is definitely
奇怪
Strange.
是啊，一点也不原始
Yeah, not that amish, really.
是啊，一点也不
No, not so much.
也许他们不知道有这个么玩意儿
在这
Maybe they don't even know it's here.
这个门最近上过油
This hatch has been oiled recently.
我们得查清楚
We have to check it out.
真的？
Really?
当然了
Of course we do.
好吧
All right.
太好了
Great.
这个建筑从技术角度来说很先进
The construction's architecturally advanced.
我认为这不是Genii人造的
I don't think the Genii could've made this.
我们必须告诉Ford我们在哪儿
We need to tell Ford where we are.
少尉，接进来
Lieutenant, come in.
Ford?
这个地方有些像碉堡
This place is built like a bunker.
这一定是为了防护R-F的
It must be shielded for R-F.
这个方向的信号强一些
The reading's stronger this way.
什么信号
What kind of readings?
——手掌信号，这个……
——McKay
- Palm readings. Is that good...
- McKay.
这是中子辐射
It's neutron radiation.
这里显然有个能量源
It's definitely a... a powerful energy source.
OK
Okay.
我们来看看
Let's check it out.
我想我们离开这儿了
I really think we should get out of here.
现在这个才叫奇怪呢
Now, this is strange.
抱歉，我要先去解决一下问题
If you'll excuse me, I must go tend to a dispute.
没事吧，Cowen？
Is everything all right, Cowen?
我很快就回来的
I will return shortly.
也许他们以两种文明方式存在着
Maybe they exist as two separate cultures.
也许了
Maybe.
管它呢
Who cares?
你们打算让我们在这儿等多久？
How long are you boys planning on keeping us here?
如果你们可以把
You know, if people could just learn to keep their
地下基地隐藏的那么好……
secret underground hatches locked...
别在提什么两种不同的存在方式了
So much for two separate cultures.
我现在该怎么办？
What am I going to do?
我心里有种异样的感觉
I'm getting a weird vibe all of a sudden.
同意
I agree.
我从没见过Genii人像现在这样
I have never seen the Genii behave this way.
我们想出去看看
Listen, we're just going to step outside
Sheppard少校和McKay博士是否回来了
and see if Major Sheppard and Dr. Mckay are back.
你们不能离开这儿，外面不安全
No one must leave. It's not safe.
附近有幽灵船出没
There's a wraith ship in the area.
幽灵？
Wraith?
你们不是在开玩笑吧？
Are you serious?
我们要去给我们的伙伴报警
We need to warn our friends.
你们会把幽灵引到这儿来的
You will draw them to us.
所有人都必须留在屋子里
Everyone must stay indoors.
你可以小心一点吗？
Oh. Can we be careful with that?
它很，它很容易摔碎，如果……
It's just, it's rather fragile, and if it, uh...
我们有个问题
We have a problem.
那我们还算有些共同点了
Then we have something in common.
通常情况下，在你们发现了我们的秘密
之后就被射杀了
Normally, you would already have been
shot for discovering our secret.
那样的话，我们的人就会来这儿
向你们讨债
In which case, more of our people would
show up and question our disappearance.
我们只要说是幽灵干的就行了
We would simply tell them the Wraith took you.
因为无以对证
With no evidence to the contrary,
他们只能相信我们
they would believe us.
你刚才想什么？
You were saying?
你们有新技术，新知识
You have technology, knowledge new to us.
你们的这个C-4……
This C-4 of yours...
不是用来拔起树根的
It's not for blowing up stumps.
我们可以用来做更复杂的事情
We have a more sophisticated application for it.
听着，你们用C-4来干吗
Look, what you people do with your c4
不关我们的事
is none of our business.
我们只要食物
We just need food.
从你们目前这地下基地的情况来看
As far as your little secret down here goes, well...
我们的意思是：多么壮观的地下碉堡啊
we say, "what giant, underground bunker?"
我需要更多的C-4
I want more than that.
呃，也许我们可以给你们……更多
Well, maybe we can give you... more.
你们有比C-4更先进的武器？
You have weapons more powerful than your C-4?
你是在开玩笑吗？武器是我们的
我们……
Are you kidding me? Weapons are us. We...
我们有
We might.
如果我不单要武器呢？
What if I wanted more than weapons?
我是不是说过我知道一切的一切？
Uh, did I mention that I know almost
everything about almost everything?
连Teyla Emmagan都加入你们了
For Teyla Emmagan to have joined with you,
你们一定有更……
you must have something much more...
我们只是想摆脱困境
Look, I'm going to go out on a limb here
我们只是在寻找对抗幽灵的同盟
and just say that we're looking
for allies against the Wraith.
你们觉得怎么样？
How about you guys?
听着，我只是想出去看看
Listen, we just want to take a look outside.
不行
We can't let you.
不安全
It's not safe.
我们会照顾好自己的
We can take care of ourselves.
Tyrus， 请回复
Tyrus, please respond.
收到
Receiving.
带走他们
Bring them.
明白
Understood.
放下武器
Relinquish your weapons.
我们就不会伤害你们
You will not be harmed.
你们总是给我们惊奇啊
You guys are full of surprises.
你们错过了丰收庆典，长官
You missed a hell of a harvest ceremony, Sir.
可以想见
I can imagine.
哦，Teyla
Oh. Teyla.
少校，我和你一样感到很奇怪
I am as surprised as you are by all of this, Major.
我不知道，我感到太奇怪了
I don't know. I'm pretty surprised.
Teyla和她的人民只知道我们所表现出来的
那一面——淳朴的农民
Teyla and her people know us only
as the simple farmers we show outsiders.
我们的身份之谜是我们对幽灵的
最好的防御武器
The secrecy of who and what we are
is the only defense we have against the Wraith.
总有一天，这会改变的
One day, all that will change.
你们以为你们可以造出原子弹吗？
You think you can do that with an atomic bomb?
现在是你们让我们搞到奇怪了
Now it's you who surprise me.
辐射信号
以及你们对C-4浓厚的兴趣
Well, radioactive readings,
your fascination with our C-4...
你现在才发现？
You're just mentioning this now?
他说“总有一天，这会改变”的时候
我才反应过来
It just came to me when he said,
"one day, all that will change."
我想你们是希望C-4能解决你们
面临的超临界问题
I assume you're hoping our C-4
will solve your supercriticality problem.
行得通吗？
Will it?
也许
It might.
跟你们的设计有关
有一些其它需要考虑的事项
Depends on your design.
There's a host of other considerations.
你知道怎么造原子弹？
You know how to make an a-bomb?
少校，我高中的国际象棋队里
大部分的队友都能设计原子弹
Major, most of my high school chess team
could design an a-bomb.
难的是获得足够的
够纯度的可分裂物质
The actual hard part is having
sufficient fissionable materials of appropriate grade.
我们有
And we do.
你们有？
You do?
Genii人以前是一个星球的联邦
The Genii were once a great confederation of planets.
几千年以前，幽灵把我们逼到了
灭绝的边缘
Millennia ago, the Wraith had driven us
to the brink of total annihilation.
我们的先祖造出了防御碉堡
就像这个一样
Our forefathers sought the protection
of bunkers such as these,
这里原先是为了战争而建的
originally created for wars long forgotten,
只有在这里，我们的人有一小部分
and it was here that a small number of our people
躲过了被发现的命运
managed to survive undetected.
时间一年年过去
Over the course of many, many years,
generation after generation
我们一代代人在这儿秘密发展科技
we have made technological developments here in secret.
所以那些耕种的东西都只是表象
So the whole farmer thing is just a front.
以使幽灵不会怀疑
So the Wraith do not suspect.
不单是这样
More than that.
我们还要养家糊口
We do have many mouths to feed below.
我想带你看些东西
I want to show you something.
跟我来
Come with me.
对了，那个你随意丢在桌上的东西……
Oh, that thing you so carelessly threw on the table...
我能带着它吗？
Can I take that along?
来吧
Come.
你们守着这里
Stay as you are.
在这地下，我们在这里训练军队
科学家们则在这发明武器
Down below, our military trains
as our scientists create weapons for them.
我们相信，有了核武器
With our atomic weapon, we believe
我们就拥有了将幽灵一举歼灭的
把握
we finally have what we need to defeat
the Wraith once and for all.
你们知道长时间暴露在核辐射下
是很危险的吧？
You do realize that long-term exposure
to these levels of radiation is extremely dangerous.
我们的科学家说的可相反
Our scientists tell me otherwise.
那么他们错了
Well, they're wrong.
我们现在危险吗？
Are we in danger now?
在这个辐射率下需要几天或几周的时间
It would take days or weeks
at these levels of radiation,
但是我相信Genii人在这儿一定不止
几天或几周了
but I assume the Genii spend days or weeks down here.
有许多人一辈子都呆在这儿
Many of our people have spent their entire lives here.
他们整个短暂的生命
Their entire, short lives.
我们没事的，只要我们不打算生小孩就行
We'll be fine, just as long as you weren't
planning on having children.
不错，你们的方向是正确的
Well, you're on the right track.
我们比你们领先60年
We're about 60 years ahead of you.
前提是，你们能活下来
That is, if you survive.
这保护层很遗憾的不够充分
This shielding is woefully inadequate.
现在，铀的问题……
Now, uranium...
你们有多少铀？
How much do you have?
很多
Much more.
远达不到造武器的标准
It's nowhere near weapons grade.
我们碰到了净化的问题
We have had problems in our purifying efforts.
杂质的分子结构和我们要的成分的分子结构
很相近
The molecular structure of the unwanted material
is very similar to that of the desired material.
扩散运动……你们必须把铀235和铀238分离开来
Diffusion... You need to separate the 235 from the 238.
当你把两种成分间的阻碍隔开
When you remove the barrier between two substances,
the slight difference in their mass
它们组成结构上的不同会使它们以不同的速率扩散
causes them to separate at different rates.
你可以做吗？
You could do this?
当然，我只是……
Well, of course. I just...
我想当下最主要的问题
I think the real question is, right now.
我们是同盟……
Are we allies...
还是囚犯？
Or are we still prisoners?
我们对新朋友感激不尽
We give thanks to our new friends.
我们感谢
We give thanks.
Please, eat.
这里没放柠檬吧，是吗？
You don't think there's lemon in this, do you?
我保证这很美味
I'm sure it's delicious.
你见过有人过敏性休克吗？
Have you seen someone in anaphylactic shock?
吃吧
Eat.
我希望这顿饭可以
弥补我们以前的冒犯
I hope that by sharing this meal
we can make up in some small way for past offenses.
我相信我们会合作愉快的
I'm sure we'll get along just fine.
你们在原型设备上是用
What method did your people use
什么方法来
to initiate fission reaction
启动分裂反应的呢？
in your prototype devices?
实际上，有两种不同的方法
Well, there's two different approaches, actually...
内裂式的和枪型的原子弹
Implosion and a gun-type bomb.
显然，这两个都设计成
能产生超临界质量
Both were designed to create
a supercritical mass, obviously.
显然
Obviously.
不论哪一种方法，你都需要精炼的铀235
Either way you go, you need an amount of refined 235
差不多要我的拳头大小那么多
roughly equivalent to the size of my fist...
或者他的拳头
Or his fist, actually.
我们的梦想就快变成现实了
Well, our dreams may soon be a reality.
有了你们的帮助，在下次提炼之前
With your help, before the next culling,
我们打算在幽灵沉睡之时蒸发
we plan to vaporize the Wraith as they sleep.
你的计划究竟是怎样的？
What exactly is your plan?
我们要利用他们的自负
We intend to take advantage of their overconfidence.
这是他们的弱点
That is their weakness.
自负
Overconfidence.
在提炼物送到他们的飞船的间隙
他们会冬眠
They hibernate between cullings aboard their great ships,
有时长达几个世纪
sometimes for centuries at a time.
他们总会有人守卫着睡觉的人
但那毕竟是少数
There are always Wraith who watch over the sleepers,
but they're small in number.
我们有能力制服
Small enough to be overpowered.
我们准备偷偷的把我们的新武器
送到他们的飞船上
We intend to sneak aboard
their ships with our new weapons.
现在不可能那样做了
That may no longer be possible.
——Teyla……
——少校？
- Teyla...
- Major?
难道你不认为在提意见之前，
我们该先听完他们整个计划吗？
Don't you think we should listen to their whole plan
before we start poking holes in it?
如果我们要在一起合作，他们需要相信我们
我们也需要相信他们
If we are to work together, then they need
to trust us and we need to trust them.
请解释一下
Please explain.
我和我的一些人曾被
幽灵抓去过
I and several of my people
had been captured by the Wraith.
你们需要知道
那是我们的救援计划
You must understand,
it was a rescue mission to save us.
我能活到今天要感谢他们
I am only alive today thanks to them.
那次救援的结果……
As a result of that rescue...
你把其它的幽灵惊醒了
You awakened the others.
他们发现我们的那个地方有更多的人
They found out that there were
more people where we came from.
爸爸，他们会都醒过来的
Father, they will all awaken.
我们活捉了一个幽灵
Look, we took one of them prisoner.
下次提炼被安排在几十年后
The next culling was supposed to be decades away.
他说他们不急
他们会耐心的跟我们周旋
He said they were in no hurry,
that they would take their time to come after us.
我们原打算5年后能进行第一次核试验呢
We had hoped to test our first
atomic weapon five years from now.
我们有那么多时间吗，Sheppard？
Do we have that much time, Sheppard?
有吗？
Do we?
没有
No.
Cowen...
他们会发现辐射
They may detect the radiation.
我们必须关闭反应堆
留下提炼物，然后再作下一步打算
We have to shut down the reactors,
survive this culling, and somehow plan for the next.
你忘记了些事
You're forgetting something...
——我们可以躲过他们
——我们在一条船上！
- We can hide from them...
- We're both on the same side...
一旦我们把需要的榨光了
Once we have extracted all
the information we can from you,
你们会被留在上面
you will be left on the surface.
你们会第一个被幽灵吞食
You'll be the first the Wraith feed upon,
我保证
I promise you.
我碰过幽灵的飞船
而且我赢了
I've gone up against Wraith ships and I won.
我见过你们的武器
I've seen your weapons...
我说的是一艘飞船
可以穿越空间的飞船
I'm talking about a ship,
one that flies through space,
上面有你见都没有见过的武器
with weapons beyond anything you've ever seen.
你真的想拒绝这样一种帮助吗？
Do you really want to turn down that kind of help?
我想你只是在为自己辩解
I think you're trying to save yourself.
是啊，真TMD被你说中了
Well, you're damn right I am.
我想我们一起合作
也许可以互相帮忙
I say we work together,
then maybe help save each other.
我们的目的是一样的
We both want the same thing.
我们开始实验是因为我们原以为
幽灵短期内不会发现
We started our experiments confident the Wraith
would not appear for many years.
现在看来他们会像你们一样发现我们的
They will detect us the same way you did.
——但是如果我们合作……
——你们还嫌不够么？
- But if we work together...
- Haven't you done enough?
我们还没开始合作呢
We haven't even started yet.
我可以使你们走回正轨
I can get your program right back on schedule.
怎么办到？
How?
我为了六年级的科学展
造了一个原子弹
I built an atomic bomb for
my grade six science fair exhibit.
在加拿大他们让你这样做？
They let you do that up in Canada?
那不是工作模型
我还为这个被中情局询问了6个小时
It wasn't a working model.
Still, I was questioned for six hours by the CIA,
他们以为我是一个未成年秘密组织的成员
who believed I was part of
a secret preteen organization.
实际上，这也是我第一份工作的……
Actually, it led to my first job...
Sheppard少校刚刚让我相信我们
还有成功的希望
Major Sheppard has convinced me
that we may yet prevail...
是吗？
He has?
如果我们精诚合作的话
If we work together.
许多年以前，再一次提炼中
Many generations ago, during a culling,
Genii成功的射下了一个幽灵的近程导弹
the Genii were able to shoot down a wraith dart.
虽然那天我们损失了很多人
Although many lives were lost that day,
损失了很多东西
the ability to resist, even in some small way,
但这至少给了我们
Genii人一点希望
gave the Genii the seeds of hope.
这个数据保存器是从击落的
幽灵近程导弹上恢复过来的
This data storage device was recovered
from that downed Wraith dart.
就像飞机失事时的黑匣子
It's like flash memory in a jump drive.
它包含了当初发射它的飞船的信息
It contains information about
the hive ship it was deployed from.
Tyrus和他的女儿已经成功破解了
上面的信息
Tyrus and his daughter have been able
to successfully access that information.
怎么破的？
How?
通过这个界面
Through this interface.
真的么？
Well, really?
我们相信
We believe...
这就是幽灵飞船休眠的地方
This is where a Wraith ship still sleeps.
幽灵善于自毁
The Wraith tend to self-destruct.
拥有这种东西还真是少见
It's probably pretty rare to get ahold
of something like this.
你们破解了其它信息了吗？
Have you been able to access any other data?
通过这个界面
我们相信我们可以破解幽灵飞船的数据核心
With this interface device, we believe
we can access the Wraith ship's data core.
这就是你们整个计划的基础？
So this is what your whole plan is based on?
那能进入幽灵飞船的电脑
对你有什么帮助吗？
Well, how does getting access
to a Wraith ship's computer help you?
通过这个设备，我们可以
知道所有幽灵飞船的方位
With this interface device, we can learn
the locations of all the Wraith ships.
所以你们知道在哪儿放你们的新炸弹了
So you know where to deliver your new bombs.
有点道理
Makes sense.
在我们看到的那条飞船仍
在原地的前提下
Assuming, of course, the ship
we're looking at is still there.
如果幽灵不急着召集他们的武装
就像你们所说的，它应该还在原处
Well, if the Wraith are in no hurry
to rally their forces, as you claim, it will be.
这飞船离星际门很远
This ship is nowhere near the Stargate.
徒步靠近它而不被发现
是不可能的
Approaching it undetected by foot is impossible.
那是你们的飞船进来的地方，少校
That is where your ship comes in, Major Sheppard.
我还奇怪我的飞船究竟从哪儿飞进来了呢
I always wondered where my ship would come in.
不行
No.
这个作为回答怎么样？
How's that for an answer?
简短有力的，拿我来说的话
It's pithy, I'll give you that.
我肯定你已经同意了
I'm sure you already agreed to this.
那也只是因为我们会取得成果
Only because we'll get something out of it.
我们确实需要同盟，长官
And we do need allies, ma'am.
同盟？
Allies?
你们刚刚说那些人想把你们捆起来
You just said these people were ready to string you up.
你们怎么能相信他们？
How can you trust them?
一旦我们不再相信他们
我们可以甩了他们
Hey, I don't trust them as far as I can throw them.
他们坚持让McKay和Teyla
留在那里的有原因的
There's a reason they insisted
that McKay and Teyla stay there,
不仅仅是为了帮助他们制造原子弹
and it's not just to help them with their bomb,
而是因为我们各有所需
but we have something they need and
they have something we need.
我想这就是我们谈判的重点
I thought that's what negotiating was all about.
嗯，是啊
Ioh, well, it is.
我以个人的名义停止向你们
供应核武器
Personally, I stop short of offering nuclear weapons.
无论如何，他们已经在造了
They were building them anyway.
如果他们在造了，那你们为什么这么说？
Oh, if they were building them anyway,
why didn't you just say so?
你们知道
我原先派你们去是为了食物的吗？
You realize I originally sent you out for food?
我想我们仍可以得到食物
I think we can still get that.
我不知道为什么不行
I don't see why not.
我们只是更进一步到了
原子弹方面的事而已
We kind of moved past it
with the whole atomic bomb thing.
好吧，最低原则，你们能成功吗？
All right, bottom line, can you pull this off?
我们得当心，但……
We'll have to watch our backs, but...
如果我认为不会成功
我就不会冒险把我的队伍置于其中
I wouldn't put my team at risk if I didn't think so.
好吧，去吧，也许我们
还有机会讨论怎么制造核弹头
Okay, go, and then maybe we'll talk
about making nuclear bombs.
那个球形箱体引导
爆炸力向内延伸
The spherical encasement directs
the explosive forces inward,
而最终的爆炸会产生极大的压缩力
and the resulting implosion
creates extreme compression.
这些次临界的物体就会变成超临界的
The subcritical mass becomes supercritical.
太天才了
Ingenious.
我知道，你能够想象
这还不足以赢得科学展吗？
I know, and can you believe
I didn't even win the science fair?
真正的挑战是对现有的仪器和资源
进行相应的改造
So, the practical adaptation of available equipment
and resources will be the real challenge.
McKay博士，你生来就是为了成为我们的英雄啊
You're destined to become a hero
among our people, Dr. Mckay.
没错
Right.
只要Sheppard带着C-4回来
As long as major Sheppard returns with the C-4.
我死定了
I'm a dead man.
我们互相都吃惊不小啊
We have surprised each other.
Genii人跟我想象的不一样啊
The Genii are not the people I thought they were.
而你呢
And look at you.
我可不敢想象你会离开你的人民
I would never have thought
that you'd leave your people.
不，我这样做是为了他们
No. I do this for them.
John Sheppard和他的人民给我的星球
带来了新希望，Sora
John sheppard and his people have brought
new hope to our stars, Sora.
他们有探险家的精神和
斗士的心
They have the spirit of explorers
and the hearts of warriors.
他们接受了我
They have accepted me.
但看看你
But look at you.
你还能参加几次我们的丰收庆典？
How many "harvest ceremonies" did I make you endure?
不了，我保证
Never again, I promise you.
你们尊重我们
You respected us for who we were.
那时我们相信你们的原因
That gave us reason to trust you.
你们认为我们不够资格分享你们的秘密
我感到很悲哀
I am saddened that you could not
trust me enough to share in your secret.
那是我们的方式
That is our way.
我们的原则是，而且将一直是，生存
Our deception was and is a matter of survival.
这是我们生来享有的秘密
我们也愿意带到棺材里去
It is a secret we are born into that
we willingly take to our graves.
那么……
Still...
难道我们没有跟你们公平交易吗？
Have we not always traded fairly with you?
你应该知道我们没有这么光明正大
的和其他人做过生意
You should know we have not dealt
with others so graciously.
也许新的联盟能让你们看清
Perhaps this new alliance
will help to open your eyes...
只有我们精诚合作
才有可能打败幽灵
That we can only stand against
the Wraith if we do so together.
我们还得观察一下你的朋友们
是不是信守诺言
We'll have to see if your friends
will live up to their promises.
嗯哼？
Well?
看见了吗？
Do you see?
我们的动作必须尽可能的快
We've got to get in and out as fast as possible.
我毕生都在研究这个计划
I've been studying these plans all my life.
好啊
Good.
那我们跟着你走
Then we'll follow your lead.
你们在做的时候我们会掩护的
We'll keep you covered during the breach and download.
撤退计划呢？
Exit plan?
和进入一样，你留在探险者号
Same as we came in. You'll stay with the jumper.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
我要和你一起去
I should be going with you.
我们很有可能碰到一场战斗
There's a good chance we could end up in a firefight.
Ford少尉，Sora是一个
训练有素的战士，并且是个神射手
Sora is a skilled fighter and
expert marksman, lieutenant Ford.
尽管如此，她必须留在这儿继续
如果我们回不来的话
Still, she must stay here
to carry on if we don't come back.
在行动之前
我们需要你们把承诺的C-4 拿过来，少校
We need you to deliver the C-4 you've promised us,
Major, before we proceed.
我们必须先找到合适的突破口
We need to get the proper intel first.
如果不能投入使用
那我们造出核武器也没用
There's no use in building a bunch of nukes
if we can't put them to use.
这是你的原则？
Those are your terms?
我相信你明白的
I'm sure you understand.
明白
I do.
看来我们除了互相信任，别无他选
It seems we have no choice but to trust each other.
你们有多少艘这种船？
How many of these ships do you have?
只有1艘
Just the one.
那里
There.
他们醒过来了吗？
Have they awoken?
我看不见任何活动
I don't see any activity.
和上次一样
Same as last time.
好吧，我们出发
All right, here we go.
从前门进去
Right through the front door.
嘿，守住这里
Hey, hold the fort.
是的，长官
Yes, sir.
好运
Good luck.
哦，天啊
Oh, god.
这些人被茧缠住了，以备以后食用
These people were cocooned for later feeding.
他们中有些可能还活着
Some of them may still be alive.
我们没时间来管这个
We don't have time for this.
他们可能是你们的人
They could be your people, for all you know.
Teyla，你看好这里
我们飞船上见
Teyla, take care of this.
We'll meet you back at the ship.
McKay，给我来
McKay, you're with me.
我留着和她一起
I'll stay with her.
走，我们飞船上见
Go.
We'll meet you back at the ship.
就是这儿了
This is it.
但我记得计划里没有
包括怎么操作这扇门啊
But the ship's plans I memorized did not
include the details on how to operate this door.
如果试图冲破这扇门
会造成很大的声响
If we try to blow this door,
it's going to make too much noise.
所以另寻他法
So find another way.
Okay.
给点亮光
Can I get some light here?
漂亮
Beautiful.
求求你……救救我
Please... help me.
我们会救你出来
We're going to get you out.
你在做什么？
What are you doing?
——我们不能放了他，我们一个都不能放
——什么？
- We cannot free him. We can save none of them.
- What?
求求你……
Please help...
你要把他们留在这里等死？
You would leave him here to die?
听着，不能让幽灵知道我们来过
Listen, the Wraith must not know we were ever here.
我说不行
I said no.
McKay，我们没有……
McKay, we don't have..
我不知道这是否……
Look, I don't even know if this is going to...
有用
Work.
瞧
Bingo.
好了
All right.
我帮你放风，去吧
I'll cover your six. Go.
如果你把他放了，他们会知道的
If you free him, they will know he was taken.
我简直不敢相信你是这样一个人
You are not the man I believed you to be.
这艘飞船离我们的星球最近
This ship is closest to our world.
如果幽灵醒来，第一个死的是Genii人
The Genii will be the first to die if they awaken.
救救我！
Help me!
我说了离他远点
I said leave him.
不！
No!
安静！
Be silent!
少校，我们被发现了
Major, we have been discovered.
我们该走了
We've got to get out of here.
搞定了
We've got it.
幽灵护卫
Wraith guards.
快，后面更多
Hurry. More are coming.
Tyrus呢？
Where's Tyrus?
他被幽灵武器击中了
He was struck by a Wraith weapon.
他也许只是昏迷了
He may have only been stunned.
现在他一定已经被幽灵抓住了
By now, the Wraith will be upon him.
走，走！
Go. Go!
好吧，别急
All right, hang on.
我爸爸呢？
Where is my father?
他没能回来
He did not survive.
怎么回事？
How?
发生什么了？
What happened?
我想我们该查查
I think we should find out.
瞄准
Take aim.
Cowen...我以为我们
已经学会怎么合作了
Cowen...
I thought we were just learning how to get along.
她杀了Tyrus
She killed tyrus.
没有
No.
你把他留下送死，当时你很可能已经
把他杀了
By leaving him to die, you may just
as well have killed him yourself.
他把我要救的人打死了
He shot the man we tried to save.
尝试去救人是一个错误
It was a mistake to try and save anyone.
这使我们的行动遇到了危险
It jeopardized the mission.
我们会留下这些智能信息
We will keep this intelligence information...
你才是制造错误的那个人
You're the one making a mistake.
你的飞船，以及无论你们拥有多少C-4
And your ship, and whatever quantities of C-4
you have in your possession.
这就是你们算计好的
要利用我们
That is all you ever intended, to use us.
为了感谢你们，我们会留你们一命
And for your efforts, I will spare your lives.
多慷慨啊
How generous of you.
我想塔瓦豆已经掉下桌子了
I guess the tava beans are off the table.
放下你们的武器
Your weapons.
不
No.
我不这么认为
I don't think so.
我们的人多，少校
We have the advantage, Major.
是啊
Yeah.
你爸爸的死就是为了这个？
This is what your father died for?
为了那些可以把朋友拿来出卖以及
洗劫的人们？
In the name of people who would lie and
steal from those they would call friends?
我也撒谎了
Well, I lied too.
探险者2号和3号，执行命令
Jumpers two and three, execute.
你们不会真的认为我们只有一艘飞船吧，啊？
You didn't really think we had one ship, did you?
让你们的人回去，大家互不伤害
Tell your people to get back and nobody gets hurt.
探险者二号，听我的号令准备开火
Jumper two, prepare to fire on my mark.
等等
Wait.
你们保证离开？
Do you promise to leave?
是啊，那是计划
Well, that's the plan.
我想我们该到其他地方找我们的
塔瓦豆了，但是……
I guess we'll have to go somewhere else
to find our tava beans, but...
我想我们该做个了结才算公平
I think it's only fair we end up with something.
你们不该和Genii人为敌的
You do not want to make an enemy of the Genii.
你知道吗？
Well, you know what?
我们也是
Same here.
少校，我猜你也许想看看这个
Major, I thought you might like to see this.
我们从数据存储器上下载的许多数据
是经过加密的
A lot of the information we downloaded
from the data storage device was encrypted,
所以我们仍然在破解它
so we're still working on that.
嗯，我知道这不容易
Yeah, I didn't think it would be easy.
但我们可以确定21艘幽灵飞船的存在
But we were able to ascertain
the existence of 21 Wraith hive ships
单单在我们所处的飞马星系的这四分之一
just in our quadrant of the Pegasus galaxy alone.
21艘？
21?
而且有暗示说在飞马的
其他地方有更多
And there are indications of
far more elsewhere in Pegasus.
那到底有多少？
Well, how many more?
没办法知道确切的数字
Well, there's no way of knowing for sure.
也许60艘，或更多
Perhaps 60... Or more.
那挺多呀
That's a lot of ships.
有些似乎已经开始行动了
Some of them already appear to be on the move.
朝我们来的？
Toward us?
我们正研究到这部分
That's the part we're still working on.
所以即使我们帮助Genii人建立了
核弹头
So even if were to have helped
the Genii build nuclear warheads...
我们也只能同时用
少量的核武器进行攻击
We only could have nuked
a handful of them simultaneously.
没错
Exactly.
对于联合攻击
这些幽灵飞船足够了
There's far too many Wraith ships
for a coordinated attack.
Genii人的计划注定要失败的
不管有没有我们的帮助
The Genii plan never would have worked,
with or without our help.
我看看还有什么
I'll see what else I can find.
谢谢，Peter
Thank you, Peter.
你也许乐意在你们走后听到Bates军士
成功的谈成了一笔粮食生意
You might be happy to know sergeant Bates was able to
broker a small trade agreement for food while you were gone.
是吗，他谈成了？
Oh, he did, did he?
没错，谈成了，但这不是和你们比赛
Yes, he did, but it's not a competition.
对方是什么样的人？
So who are these people?
他们是商人
They're traders.
他们自称为Manarian人
They call themselves Manarians.
John，我很抱歉你没有找到
你想要的同盟
I'm sorry you weren't able to find
the allies you're looking for, John.
但我们得到了一些有用的信息
这也算收获
Well, we gathered some valuable intel.
That's something.
你是想让我认为你这次行动成功了吗？
You're trying to convince me this is good news?
我宁愿我们提前知道面临什么
而不是蒙在鼓里
I much prefer to know what
we're up against than not.
60艘飞船……或许更多
60 ships...
Or more.
我现在只希望他们不要同时来
I just hope they don't all come at once.